I think data is actually really exciting.
我觉得数据真的很让人兴奋
I feel like data is really just information.
我觉得数据实际上就是信息
And so, the more information that you have,
因此你拥有越多信息
the better decision that you can make.
你越能做出更好的决定
My name is Sinthuja, and I'm a Manager of Data Analytics at Summit Public Schools.
我叫 Sinthuja 是 Summit 公立学校的数据分析负责人
I've actually had a few different roles.
其实我之前还做过别的工作
I worked a little bit in consulting and then decided to be a teacher.
我曾经短暂地做过咨询 之后又决定当老师
And data was actually, just seemed like the perfect fit for me,
而数据实际上就像是为我量身定制的一样
because it makes my previous teaching experience,
因为它能给我之前
at working in an education company,
在教育公司工作的教学经验
with also a more technical aspect as well.
增添更多技术背景
So, Summit public schools is actually a charter management organization, a nonprofit,
Summit 公立学校实际上是个特许经营组织 一个非营利机构
and we have developed
我们开发了自己的平台
our own platform that we partnered with the Chan Zuckerberg initiative.
我们的平台和“陈·扎克伯格倡议”慈善机构合作
They store all the student grades data
他们在数据库里储存了所有学生的成绩数据
and also how they're interacting with the platform,
以及他们与平台的交互方式
in that database, and that's really what we use to analyze.
而这些正是我们用来分析的对象
One of the projects that I'm really excited about is
让我很兴奋的一个项目是
analyzing and tracking student performance data,
分析和跟踪学生学习表现的数据
and actually building tools for school leaders and teachers in
使用 tableau 作为学校领导和老师的开发工具
tableau and displaying that data for them to use on a weekly or daily basis.
并展示数据给他们看 好让他们每周甚至每天都能够利用这些数据
I've actually had the privilege of doing focus groups
我还有幸组织了焦点小组
and user experience interviews with school leaders and teachers to
对学校领导和老师进行用户体验采访
develop an experience that they can really use to improve outcomes of their schools.
从而提升体验 让他们能真正用来改进学校成果
I've seen Summit grow from both a small organization to a large,
我见证了 Summit 从一个小组织发展成大机构
and even when you're small you have to figure out a lot of things on your own of like,
哪怕是小组织 也得亲自搞懂很多事情
how the data is structured and being able to analyze it in the correct way.
比如数据结构是什么样的 怎样才能正确分析数据
But once we built the data infrastructure,
哪怕我们建好了数据架构
you still have to really be able to like think about questions on your own,
你还是得学会独立思考问题
and lead projects, and ask what's the next step that I want to do with this analysis.
领导项目 学会如何在下一步利用分析结果
So, I think dealing with ambiguity is going to be a key part of any data analyst role.
所以我认为处理不确定性是任何数据分析人员的工作关键
I think as long as you have like a good foundation in SQL,
我觉得只要你有 SQL 的良好基础
and then also some statistical background,
再有一些统计学的背景知识
whether that could be in Python, in R,
无论是用 Python、R
or Stata, like all of
还是 Stata 的背景
those languages will really set you up to be a successful data analyst.
这些语言都能给你打下良好的基础 让你成为成功的数据分析师
And it's really just understanding a data infrastructure and
这类职位其实就是要理解数据架构
how your data systems are set up,
明白数据系统是怎么建立的
and then being able to join everything and just
懂得如何结合所有事物
aggregate and analyze in a way that makes sense.
合理地进行整合并分析
One of the key things that I've learned is that there is always something new to learn.
我从过去学到的很重要一点是 学无止境
So, even though I feel like I've developed a lot of skill in SQL and Python,
就算觉得自己学会了很多 SQL 和 Python 的技巧
I'm always trying to figure out what's like
我还是经常在找
the next thing that I can learn to improve my skill set.
一些可以学习的事物来提升技能
I've tried a lot of different programs in order to increase my skill set, and yeah,
为了提升技能 我还试过很多不同的课程
my favorite course has actually been one of the courses that I took on Udacity,
我最喜欢的是优达学城上过的一门课
mainly because of the project based learning.
主要是因为它学以致用的教学方式
I think that online learning is great,
我觉得在线学习很棒
and like you can delve into topics on your own pace,
你可以按自己的节奏来钻研各种主题
but actually being able to apply it,
但将所学加以实践
is really where you learn a lot,
才是你能学到最多的地方
and you learn what you know,
你将知道自己会什么
what you don't know,
不会什么
and also it just really stretches your thinking in a different way, and so,
这种实践能够拓展你的思路
Udacity's courses where they force you to kind of do that project at
优达学城的课程会在单元结束后
the end of the unit are actually super beneficial and I would highly recommend them.
让你去做必修项目 这真的很有用 我极力推荐这样的课
I think that the data analysts role is going to be an integral part of any company,
我觉得数据分析师将是所有公司不可或缺的岗位
as our society has so much access to data and it's only going to continue to grow.
因为我们的社会有那么多获取数据的途径 而数据只会越来越多
That if you have a data analyst background,
一旦你有了数据分析的背景
it really will set you up to be successful in any types of roles that you have later on.
你就能做好准备 在未来的任何职业中取得成功